Guide to the Historic Photograph Subject File circa 19th century-20th century
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Historic Photograph Subject File
circa 19th century-20th century
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
PC 2
37 Boxes
The Historic Photograph Subject File contains photographs taken throughout the Pacific Northwest and Alaska that cover a wide variety of subjects.
The Historic Photograph Subject File contains photographs taken throughout the Pacific Northwest and Alaska that cover a wide variety of subjects.
The collection is arranged into 25 series based on general subject areas.
This collection is open and available for research use.
This collection started with a core of photographs taken during the 1930s as part of the Federal Writers Project for the production on the American Guide. Subsequently, the Historic Photograph Subject File was expanded through gifts and some purchases.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Northwest, Pacific -- Photographs; Alaska -- Photographs
Idaho; Alaska; Photographs; British Columbia; Montana; Oregon
- Series 1: Agriculture
  - Subseries 1.1: Agriculture: Farming
    - Sod House, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Sod Houses, 3 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Soil Conservation - erosion control in Whitman and Garfield Counties, 1937-1938, 5 items (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Barnyard Scene, c. 1910, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Yakima Valley Irrigation, c. 1919, 3 items (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Gully Stabilization Dams, Klickitat Co., 1937, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Farming-plowing, Caterpillar Tractor, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Farming-plowing, 4 bottom plow, c. 1930, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Farming-seeding, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Farming-plowing, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Farming-plowing, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Farming-plowing, Caterpillar pulling John Deere plow, June 11, 1938, Walla Walla Co., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Farming-plowing, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Caterpillar tractor plowing, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - International Harvester, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Sweet Clover being plowed under as a green manure crop, May 1938, Columbia Co., 2 items (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Trucks dumping pea silage, c. 1935, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Burning for pea pest, Boll Weevil, c. 1935 Chehalis, WA, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Preparing ground for pea seed, c. 1935 Chehalis, WA, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Pea field ready to harvest, c. 1935 Chehalis, WA, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Prize contest corn, 1909 Waitsburg, WA, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Farmhouse - Shimd family, Stevens Co., 12 items (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Agriculture - greenhouse, blacksmith, and eggs c. 1900, 3 items (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Filling a pit silo, Easter, Warden WA Grant Co., 1 item (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Farm houses near Pullman, WA, c. 1912, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Grain Wagons, harvest horses, and farm scene, 4 items (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Daffodil Field - postcard, western WA, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Cultivated Evergreen Blackberry field Puyallup Valley, WA 1935, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Bill Achorzman farm near Quincy, WA 1913, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Davis home Cashup, WA 1913, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Farming - Caterpillar tractor discing, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Farming - Experimental plot, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Champion cow - Carnation milk farm near Seattle 1936; fair scene; group, 3 items (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Berry farming - Puyallup Valley, WA blackberry field, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Pea farming - Puyallup Valley, WA, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Harrowing ground for seed bed, Skagit Co, WA, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Bush farm, January 1947 - Pullman WA, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Otto Reise with Caterpillar Diesel D2 model tractor, Puyallup WA, 3 items (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Professor O.J. Trenary farming with Army Jeep, October 2, 1943, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Windmill irrigation on wheat farm Quincy, WA, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Farmhouses and fields, c. 1930, Palouse WA, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Farm pictures - farm hand, July 1936 Goldendale, WA, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Daffodil Bulb farm - Puyallup Valley, WA, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Hop field being prepared, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Pullman farmer's produce exhibit, Thompson Fairview Ranch, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Common economic weeds, Walter Bramel Photo, 1898, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Common economic weeds 1898, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Common economic weeds 1898, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Common economic weeds 1898, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Common economic weeds 1898, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Common economic weeds 1898, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Common economic weeds 1898, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Common economic weeds 1898, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Common economic weeds 1898, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Grape production, Yakima WA, c. 1950, 3 items (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Jesse Gray farm Pullman, WA c. 1935, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Farming family, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Miscellaneous early Washington scenes - Farming, 16 items (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Farm in Washington, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Subseries 1.2: Agriculture: Harvesting
    - Four horse wagon with grain sacks, 2 items (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Horse drawn combine - Whitman Co, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Wheat harvest - Caterpillar Diesel RD4, Endicott, Aug. 13 1938, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Michael Shultheis farm Colton, WA, 28 items (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Steam stationary harvesting, Hatley's Ranch c. 1900, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Threshing crew - Big Bend region, 2 items (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Harvesting near Walla Walla with horse drawn combine, 2 items (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Harvesting near Moscow ID with horse drawn combine, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Wheat harvest - SE Washington c. 1919, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Harvest scene - steam tractor crew, 1904, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Wheat harvest - Marshall WA 1904, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Horse drawn combine and crew, 2 items (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Threshing outfit, c. 1917, 2 items (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - E.L. Arraman threshing crew, Ed Young's place c. 1917, 2 items (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Wheat harvest, Garfield WA, 2 items (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - M.D. Jensen outfit Oakesdale, WA, 2 items (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Wheat harvest Ritzville, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Threshing outfit, c. 1910, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Harvest stacking sacks, 2 items (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Warehouse of sacked wheat, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Wheat fields Walla Walla Co July, 1936, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 21)
    - Oat harvest, Skagit Valley, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 22)
    - Horse-drawn combine, Holt, 1909, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 23)
    - Wheat harvest 1900, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 24)
    - Homer Toalger in Alaska wheat, Union Flat Pullman, 1909, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 25)
    - Oats harvest and steam threshing, Oct. 21, 1936, 5 items (Box 2a, Folder 26)
    - Wheat harvest, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 27)
    - Wheat harvest, Franklin Co. WA, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 28)
    - Wheat harvest - Russel Ranch, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 29)
    - Wheat harvest shocks, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 30)
    - Thornton-St. John, John McCave Ranch, 1909, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 31)
    - Threshing steam, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 32)
    - Wheat harvesting - Oakesdale 1915, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 33)
    - Field crew at harvest, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 34)
    - Harvest - Spokane WA, fall 1897, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 35)
    - Horse drawn combine - Palouse 1898, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 36)
    - Winter barley and wheat, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 37)
    - Wheat field on Palouse, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 38)
    - Shocked wheat, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 39)
    - Harvesting near Union Town, c. 1910, 12 items (Box 2a, Folder 40)
    - Threshing crew on Colville Reservation, c. 1910, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 41)
    - Snyder farm near Pullman packing bedding, 1912, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 42)
    - Water wagon near Pullman, 1912, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 43)
    - Self-propelled combine near W.S.C. campus, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 44)
    - Threshing outfit c. 1910, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 45)
    - Harvest scene, 4 items (Box 2a, Folder 46)
    - Harvest near Colton - steam unit, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 47)
    - Various stages of wheat harvest, Colfax and Pullman WA, 5 items (Box 2a, Folder 48)
    - Various harvest scenes, 1920's, 14 items (Box 2a, Folder 49)
    - Horse-drawn combines, 10 items (Box 2a, Folder 50)
    - Harvest, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 51)
    - Harvest crew, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 52)
    - Harvesting with tractors vs. harvesting with mules, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 53)
    - Fires from smut explosion - Pullman, 1914, 3 items (Box 2a, Folder 54)
    - Threshing and sacking grain, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 55)
    - Threshing and sacking grain, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 56)
    - Harvest and thresher outfit in Missouri c. 1900, P.H. Matson 1915, 3 items (Box 2a, Folder 57)
    - John Deere harvester, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 58)
    - Steam thresher, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 59)
    - Wheat harvest near Goldendale, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 60)
    - Wheat harvest - Case combine, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 61)
    - Wheat harvest - Case-combine, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 62)
    - Wheat harvest - horse-drawn, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 63)
    - Wheat harvest postcard, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 64)
    - Heading wheat near Big Bend region of WA, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 65)
    - Caterpillar Diesel RD6 model Aug. 8, 1936, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 66)
    - Caterpillar Diesel RD6 model Aug. 12, 1938, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 67)
    - Wheat harvest 1, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 68)
    - Palouse harvest scene, 2 items (Box 2a, Folder 69)
    - Machine threshing - Big Bend district, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 70)
    - Horse drawn combine, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 71)
    - Grain loading onto truck Sept. 4, 1935, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 72)
    - Wagons hauling sacked wheat, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 73)
    - Stacking grain sacks, 3 items (Box 2a, Folder 74)
    - Push binder on Palouse, 1920, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 75)
    - Wheat harvest, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 76)
    - Ed Davis thresher outfit, 1893, 3 items (Box 2a, Folder 77)
    - Wheat harvest, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 78)
    - Horse drawn combine harvester scene postcard, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 79)
    - Harvest - Kester D. Christian 1900, 3 items (Box 2a, Folder 80)
    - Rhodes harvester, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 81)
    - Harvest crew, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 82)
    - Threshing and sacking, c. 1890, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 83)
    - Field hands sifting soil, 1 item (Box 2a, Folder 84)
    - Haying, Frank Scott Farm, St. Joe, ID, 1900, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Stacking hay - Yakima Valley, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Hay harvest - Skagit Valley, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Hay fields and shocked wheat, 1921, 3 items (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Harvest truck and loader, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Mowing, bunching and shocking hay, 1930, 5 items (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Hop pickers tent camps, c. 1930, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Hop picking crew - Moxee, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Stacking hay - Lincoln Co., 1905, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Hoeing Vegetables, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Interior Tram - Snake River, 4 items (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Cherry Picker - Yakima Valley, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Royal Ann Cherries, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 12.1)
    - Cranberry picking, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Berry harvest scene, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Berry harvest, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Berry harvest - R.D. Bodle camp, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Raspberry picker, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Raspberry harvest - Puyallup, c. 1935, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Orchard on Thompson R. - Kamloops, B.C., 1 item (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Migrant fruit camp in Yakima Valley, c. 1935, 3 items (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Hops Harvest, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 20.1)
    - Selling/Picking fruit and vegetables in western Washington, 6 items (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Fruit Dryer - building foundation at Truax 1903, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Peshastin Fruit Growers Assn., 2 items (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Kennewick Fruit Growers Assn., c. 1914, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Alfalfa Stacking near Goldendale, 1936, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Barley field near Ellensburg, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Cabbage field near Spokane, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Celery harvest near Spokane, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Daffodils - Puyallup Valley, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Lettuce field - Monroe, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Onion harvest - Kelowna, B.C., 1 item (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Onion harvest - Kelowna, B.C., 1 item (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Onion seed harvest, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Potato harvest - Kennewick, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Potato harvest - Lewis Co., 1 item (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Silage corn near Grandview, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Squash field - Nisqually Valley, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Tomatoes - Kamloops, B.C., 1 item (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Tomato harvest - Okanagan Valley, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Spokane Fruit Fair, 1895, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Palouse Harvest Fair, 1913, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Palouse Harvest Fair, 1913, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Subseries 1.3: Agriculture Irrigation
    - Irrigation - Kittitas Valley, March 3, 1938, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Columbia Basin before irrigation, 3-3-38, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Irrigation - water pump, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Irrigation - before Snipes Mt. pumping plant, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Irrigation syphon - Natchez Gap, North Yakima, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Irrigating water wheel - N. Yakima, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Yakima Valley irrigation system, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Water wheels, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Ditching with steam land dredge, Moxee Valley 1910, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Drainage ditch near Sunnyside, 1910, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Drainage ditch made with steam dredge - Yakima Valley, 1910, 1 item (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - "The Weir" - Okanagan, WA - first government irrigation project in the U.S., 1 item (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Sunnyside canal - south branch 1912; undated, 2 items (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Subseries 1.4: Agriculture Machinery
    - Caterpillar tractor, 1936, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - John Deere combine, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Combines, 6 items (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Farmall tractor, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Caterpillar tractor, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Case Combine, 1938, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Horse-drawn combine, 1941, 3 items (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Tractor and combine, Diamond, WA, 1938, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Caterpillar tractor with grain wagons, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Road construction equipment, 4 items (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Horse equipment, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Tractor and combine, 1938, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Pea floatation - Walla Walla Canning Co., 1938, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Tractor at Pullman airport, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Mill, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Plow, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Tractor pulling pea vine and loader, Chehalis 1935, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Tractor and combine, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Combine - Ritzville, 1936, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Tractor and combine, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Steel-wheeled tractor, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Tractor and plow - Uniontown, 1938, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Seed planter - Skagit Co., 1 item (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Tractor and combine near Thornton, 1938, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Pea vine harvest - Dayton, WA, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Misc. Farm Equipment, 14 items (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Steam powered farm equipment, c. 1961 including newspaper clipping from 1888, 13 items (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Early tillage implement, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Weeding implement, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Early tillage implement, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Early tillage implement, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Early tillage implement, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Early tillage implement, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Early tillage implement, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Early tillage implement, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Early tillage implement, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Early tillage implement, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Early tillage implement, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Truck converted to tractor, 1944, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Tractor and disc, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Three-bottom gang plow Whitman Co., 1 item (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Tractor and disc, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Caterpillar tractor and plow, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Tractor and harrower, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Tractor and plow, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Rod weeding with caterpillar tractor, 1938, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Tractor and plow, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Sprayer and Coastal WA Experiment Station, 1946, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Hop-picking machine, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Grain shocker with horses, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Clearing trees and brush, 1917, 4 items (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Horse-drawn combine near Waitsburg, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Tractor dealership, K.W. Carter, Pullman, 1930s, 6 items (Box 4, Folder 52.5)
    - Swather in pea fields - Walla Walla and Chehalis, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Pea harvesting c. 1935, 10 items (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Subseries 1.5: Agriculture Orchards
    - Apple sorting, packing and hauling, c. 1920's, 4 items (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - "The Apple Story", photos from 1920's - 1950's, 18 items (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Apple orchard and packed box, Skookum label, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Apple orchard - Wenatchee Valley, and apple picking - Yakima Valley, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Apple picking - ladders, c. 1920, 3 items (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Orchards on Snake River, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Apple picking near Peshastin, WA, 3 items (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Peshastin fruit growers assn., c. 1920, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Loading apple boxes on wagon - Okanagan Valley, B.C., 1 item (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Apple orchard near Wenatchee, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Apple Orchard, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 64.1)
    - Pear orchard in Yakima, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Apples - spraying and orchard scene, 4 items (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Stationary spray plant, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Van Doren Apple Box dumper, c. 1950, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Orchards in bloom, 3 items (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Apple trees in blossom - Yakima, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Orchard alkali damage, 1910, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Apple packing plant - Oliver, B.C., 1 item (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Unloading trucks and warehouse, c. 1930's, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Hydraulic sprayer, 1926, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Subseries 1.6: Agriculture Farm Animals
    - Sheep farm - Kittitas Valley, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Sheep - Walla Walla, Co, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Sheep - Kittitas Co. - A.D. Morrison's September 3, 1936, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Sheep farming, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Sheep and dogs - Kittitas Co. 9/4/36, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Hampshire sheep - Yakima Valley, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Dairy farm - Spokane Co., 1 item (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Dairy plant, 1920's, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Dairy farm - Fred Metcalfe near Locke, WA, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Dairy man's co-op creamery - Caldwell, ID, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Dairy farm - western WA, experiment station Puget Sound Basin, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Dairy farm near Sequim, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Overgrazed range land, American Falls, ID September 29, 1934, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Commercial Dairy Farm - western Washington, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Dairy herd - Puget Sound, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Poultry - Alderwood manor, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Swine farm - Tekoa, WA, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Poultry - chicken hatchery, incubator interior Kent, WA, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Poultry - Egg hatchery, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Poultry - Lewis Co. turkeys, 1937, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Rodeo Events, 5 items (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Ellensburg rodeo - "Air Flow Ride", 1 item (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Harness maker - Goldendale, WA, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Draft horse, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Rounding up horses - Baker, OR, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Horses and wagon, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Pendleton and Endicott rodeos, 1911-1912, 28 items (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Branding the calf - Baker, OR, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Hereford cattle - Pullman, WA, 1938, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Northwest cattlemen, 1835-1960, 4 items (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - "Dairy to Beef" - Miles City, MT, 1916, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - "Cattle on the Desert - Lake Co. Oregon" post card, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 31A)
- Series 2: Alaska
  - Northern lights (Aurora Borealis) over Fairbanks, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Glaciers, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 32.1)
  - Alaskan Highway, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 32.2)
  - Mastodon and other bones - Yukon Terr., 1910, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Stage Coach Sled - Yukon Terr., 1911, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Pan of gold nuggets - Quartz Creek, Yukon Terr., 1 item (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Cushman Street - Fairbanks, AK, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Fairbanks - Radio station/broad casting booth, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Fairbanks - Roman Catholic Church, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Fairbanks - snow covered cabins, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Fairbanks - orchestra, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Fairbanks - 2nd Ave. during carnival, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Fairbanks - Cushman Ave. parade, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Fairbanks - Ice Palace 1938, 4 items (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Fairbanks - plane and crew, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Fairbanks - the day the Japanese plane landed c. 1938, 4 items (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Haines, AK, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 45.1)
  - University of Alaska at Fairbanks, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 45.2)
  - Tourists at Mt. McKinley park, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Mt. McKinley in McKinley Park, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 46.1)
  - McKinley Park Hotel, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 46.2)
  - Nome, AK - passengers landing, June 9, 1906, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Nome, AK - after blizzard of 1935, 11 item (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Alaskan Beauty Queens, 4 items (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Miss Yukon, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Miss Alaska - 1938, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Miss Nome, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Yukon Territory mining scenes - Gold Run Creek and Dominion Creek, 17 items (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Dragline at Ester Creek, 2 items (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Ester Creek mining scenes, 10 items (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Steamship at Alaskan coastal town, 1 item (Box 5, Folder 56)